Hi! I'm Dr. Eric Sayer from Sayer Family Chiropractic. In this segment, we're going to be talking about some of the herbal or nutritional types of things that can be used to treat low back strains.
Of course, we've got herbal muscle relaxants.
There's numerous types.
I've got a couple different types here.
We find that certain herbs will work really for some people and not for other people.
I tell my patients you might try this brand.
If it works for you, great.
If it doesn't, we can try a couple different types of brands just to find out which works better for the person.
They're just muscle relaxants.
They're not the type that might be like prescription.
They don't knock a person out.
They can still operate heavy equipment.
They can still do what they need to.
It just takes the edge off and calms their muscles down.
A lot of people use them as sleep aides, but they work very well.
There are also herbal anti- inflammatories.
There are also nutritional or herbal supplements that are designed to strengthen ligaments, tendons, muscles, and that's all they're designed to do is just make the body work they way it should with nourishment.